Guide to the Stanford University, Publication Services, Word Graphics Photographs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Publication Services, Word Graphics photographs
1931-1961
PC0089
Stanford University. Publication Services. Word Graphics.
0.75 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer
Information about Access
None.
Separated Materials
The following damaged negatives were discarded:
35 mm negatives of a Sterling event 8x10 negative of Dr. Edward Curtis Franklin, red chalk drawing, 1937 8x10 negative of Dr. A. T. Murray and wife (number 466) 4x5 negative of orchestra or band conductor 4x5 negative of construction scene
Scope and Content
This collection consists largely of photonegatives, with a few photoprints and color transparencies. Images include portraits of faculty and staff, 1931-1951; pre-registration meeting, September 1941; two images of the exterior of the home of Prof. Robert Swain, 1936; campus buildings; and miscellaneous campus life. Of note among the portraits are seven images of Prof. P. A. Ross with x-ray equipment, 1931. Many of these images were taken by Berton W.Crandall, professional photographer. There is also a series of negatives by Stanford Daily photographers, 1961 and undated; of note are images of an anti nuclear bomb rally on campus, the old bike shop, a stunt done with Dean of Students Donald Winbigler, and the Encina Hall lobby when women students were first housed there.
Collection Contents
- Portraits (Crandall images), 1931-1951 (Box 1)
  - Cubberley, Dr. and Mrs. (with print), October 1936; 89.001
  - Culver, George (with print), Apr-31; 89.002
  - Culver, George at his desk (with print), Apr-31; 89.003
  - Emerson, James G. (with print), n.d., 89.004
  - Emerson, James G. in classroom ,n.d., 89.005
  - Farnsworth, Paul R. in office, Oct-47; 89.006
  - Fish, J. C. L. (with print), Oct-35; 89.007
  - Fish, J. C. L. (with print), Oct-35; 89.008
  - Franklin, Edward Curtis (with print), n.d., 89.009
  - Grant, Eugene (with print), Jan-51; 89.010
  - Grant, Eugene (with print), Jan-51; 89.011
  - Hall, V. E. (with print), Oct-42; 89.012
  - Lutz, Ralph (with print), n.d., 89.013
  - McDowell, John Ezra (half-tone neg with print), n.d., 89.014
  - MacFarland, Frank, print only, n.d., 89.015
  - Marx, Guido H. (with print), June 1936; 89.016
  - Marx, Guido H. (with print), June 1936; 89.017
  - Marx, Guido H. (with print), June 1936; 89.018
  - Masters, Alfred R. (copy neg with print), n.d., 89.019
  - Moreno, H. C. (copy neg with print), July 1942; 89.020
  - Morris, Sam B. (with print), Feb-42; 89.021
  - Morris, Sam B. (with print), Feb-42; 89.022
  - Moser, Charles, Oct-40; 89.023
  - Smith, Dr. Gilbert M. (with print), Oct-48; 89.024
  - Smith, Mrs. Gilbert M. (with print), Jan-50; 89.025
  - Reynolds, Leon (with print), Aug-51; 89.026
  - Rich, W. H. (with print), May 1934; 89.027
  - Ross, P. A. (with print), x-ray experiment 1, Jan-31; 89.028
  - Ross, P. A (with print), x-ray experiment 2, Jan-31; 89.029
  - Ross, P. A (with print), x-ray experiment 3, Jan-31; 89.030
  - Ross, P. A (with print), x-ray experiment 4, Jan-31; 89.031
  - Ross, P. A. (with print), x-ray experiment 5, Jan-31; 89.032
  - Ross, P. A. (with print), x-ray experiment 6, Jan-31; 89.033
  - Ross, P. A (with print), x-ray experiment 7, Jan-31; 89.034
  - Rowell, E. Z. (with print), Sep-34; 89.035
  - Rowell, E. Z. (with print), Sep-34; 89.036
  - Rowell, E. Z., Sep-34; 89.037
  - Schultz, E. W., May 1936; 89.038
  - Schultz, E. W., May 1936; 89.039
  - Schultz, E. W., May 1936; 89.040
  - Schultz, E. W., May 1936; 89.041
  - Schultz, E. W., May 1936; 89.042
  - Snyder, J. O., June 1936; 89.043
  - Snyder, J. O., June 1936; 89.044
  - Snyder, J. O., June 1936; 89.045
  - Snyder, J. O., June 1936; 89.046
  - Snyder, J. O., June 1936; 89.047
  - Taylor, Alonzo, n.d., 89.048
  - Taylor, C.V. (copy neg of portrait), Apr-46; 89.049
  - Vernier (prof. in Law School), Apr-51; 89.050
  - Whittier, Clarke Butler (Law School), Apr-51; 89.051
  - Wilbur, R. L., 50th birthday "thank you" card negative, 89.052
  - Botany professors (Abrams, Knoche, Peirce, Campbell, Cannon, Wight), June 1939; 89.053
  - Botany professors (Abrams, Knoche, Peirce, Campbell, Cannon, Wight), June 1939; 89.054
  - Botany professors (Abrams, Knoche, Peirce, Campbell, Cannon, Wight), June 1939; 89.055
- Copy negatives of portraits (Box 2)
  - Allen, Warren, 89.056
  - Carroll, Dr., 89.057
  - Cathcart, A. M., 89.058
  - Cotton, Aylett R., 89.059
  - Cottrell, Edwin, 89.060
  - Cubberley, Wilbur, and Kefauver, 89.061
  - Cutler, Leland, 89.062
  - Cutler, Leland, 89.063
  - Gray, H. D., 89.064
  - Ichihashi, Yamato, 89.065
  - Ichihashi, Yamato, 89.066
  - Kirkwood, M. R., 89.067
  - Kefauver, Grayson, 89.068
  - Lyman, Edw. D., 89.069
  - Roth, A. E., 89.070
  - Sears, J. B., 89.071
  - Storey, Tom, 89.072
  - Strickler, D., 89.073
  - Terman, Lewis, 89.074
  - Walker, Frank, 89.075
  - Unidentified No. 1, 89.076
  - Unidentified No. 2, 89.077
  - Unidentified No. 3, 89.078
  - Unidentified No. 4, 89.079
  - Unidentified No. 5, 89.080
  - Unidentified No. 6, 89.081
- Miscellaneous Crandall Images, 1936-1941 (Box 2)
  - Pre-registration meeting #1 (with print), 20-Sep-41; 89.082
  - Pre-registration meeting (with print), 20-Sep-41; 89.083
  - Pre-registration meeting (with print), 20-Sep-41; 89.084
  - Pre-registration meeting #4 (with print), 20-Sep-41; 89.085
  - Pre-registration meeting #5 (with print), 20-Sep-41; 89.086
  - Pre-registration meeting #6 (with print), 20-Sep-41; 89.087
  - Pre-registration meeting #7 (with print), 20-Sep-41; 89.088
  - Swain (Robert) Home (with print), Mar-36; 89.089
  - Swain (Robert) Home (with print), Mar-36; 89.090
- Stanford Daily Images, 1961 and undated (Box 2)
  - Winter quarter registration - 1, 89.091
  - Winter quarter registration - 2, 89.092
  - Winter quarter registration - 3, 89.093
  - Construction scene, Daily file no. 157, 89.094
  - Buttresses on Quad arches, Daily file no. 170, 89.095
  - Library reading room (lower level), Daily file no. 199, 89.096
  - Construction work/repair in building, Daily file no. 202, 89.097
  - Woman with keys, Daily file no. 204, 89.098
  - Shipping boxes addressed to Prof. Fisher, Hoover Library, Daily file no. 205, 89.099
  - Welcome sign in Encina Hall when it was used for women students, Daily file no. 236, 89.100
  - Male students (frat members?) installing lion statue outside house, Daily file no. 246, 89.101
  - Cartoon of Snoopy by Schulz "For the Daily", Daily file no. 455A, 89.102
  - "How Much is the Dean Worth?" student stunt with Dean Winbigler, Daily file no. 602 (with print), 89.103
  - Coffee Hour (students drinking coffee with professor or administrator), Daily file no. 622, 89.104
  - Big Game Bonfire, Daily file no. 631, 89.105
  - Policeman writing parking ticket, Daily file no. 645, 89.106
  - Students talking with Professor in classroom, Daily file no. 685, 89.107
  - Anti-nuclear bomb rally on campus, Daily file no. 691, 89.108
  - Anti-nuclear bomb rally on campus, Daily file no. 692, 89.109
  - Anti-nuclear bomb rally on campus, Daily file no. 695, 89.110
  - Pres. Sterling with student James Melton, Daily file no. 762, 89.111
  - Five men at lectern in classroom, Daily file no. 860 (1), 89.112
  - Five men at lectern in classroom, Daily file no. 860 (2), 89.113
  - Arriving at dorm (with prints), Daily file no. 873, 89.114
  - Arriving at dorm (with print), Daily file no. 873, 89.115
  - Old bike shop by Jerry Rankin, Sept. 1961, Daily file no. 923B (1), 89.116
  - Old bike shop by Jerry Rankin, Sept. 1961, Daily file no. 923B (2), 89.117
  - Old bike shop by Jerry Rankin, Sept. 1961, Daily file no. 923B (3), 89.118
  - Clock in tree, 1961, Daily file no. 927, 89.119
  - Harmony House, Oct. 1961, Daily file no. 976, 89.120
  - Merski gag shots (looking at Daily in inner quad), 89.121
  - Merski gag shots (looking at Daily outside English dept. door), 89.122
  - Merski gag shots (looking at Daily in arcade), 89.123
  - Merski gag shots (looking at Daily in inner quad), 89.124
  - Merski gag shots (looking at Daily outside English dept. door), 89.125
  - Merski gag shots (looking at Daily inside a classroom), 89.126
- Miscellaneous Images, undated (Box 3)
  There is no photographer identification for any of these images.
  - Crowd in front of Memorial Auditorium, oblique view, 89.127
  - Crowd in front of Memorial Auditorium, oblique view, 89.128
  - Crowd in front of Memorial Auditorium, oblique view, 89.129
  - Crowd in front of Memorial Auditorium, oblique view, 89.130
  - Toyon Hall lounge, 89.131
  - Laboratory image (probably chemistry), 89.132
  - Cheerleaders at train, 89.133
  - Students at train (Sunset Limited), 89.134
  - Possible registration scene, 89.135
  - Kathy Page sitting at table in oval, 89.136
  - Commencement scene, Frost Amphitheater, 89.137
  - Commencement scene, Frost Amphitheater, 89.138
  - Commencement scene, Frost Amphitheater, 89.139
  - Commencement scene, Frost Amphitheater, 89.140
  - Copy of photo of man in uniform, 89.141
  - People waiting in line, 89.142
  - Choir rehearsal in Memorial Church, 89.143
  - Choir rehearsal, 89.144
  - Quad images: wrought iron gate, bicycles under arcade, 89.145
  - Unidentified man, 89.146
  - Western Conference of Teamsters, 89.147
  - Western Conference of Teamsters, 89.148
  - Unidentified women in saris, 89.149
  - Unidentified women in saris, 89.150
  - Unidentified women in saris, 89.151
  - Portraits of three men at work, one is identified as Doug Whitaker (35mm strip with contact print), 89.152
  - Presentation of album "Mark 10" to Pres. Sterling (35 mm strip), 89.153
- Color Transparencies, undated (Box 3)
  - Campus scenes, 2 items: 2.5 x 2.5 inch
  - Commencement scenes, Frost Amphitheater, 9 items: 4 x 6 inch
  - Buildings: Encina, History Corner, Quad Portal, 4 items: 4 x 6 inch
  - Miscellaneous: daffodil in beer bottle with unfocused Hoover Tower in background, 1 item: 4 x 6 inch
  - Buildings: ivy-covered dorm, Quad Portal, center Quad entrance, 4 items: 5 x 7 inch